The destiny of a people lies in the heart of a boy.
Kundun is a drama, history film directed by Martin Scorsese.
The Tibetans refer to the Dalai Lama as 'Kundun', which means 'The Presence'.
He was forced to escape from his native home, Tibet, when communist China
invaded and enforced an oppressive regime upon the peaceful nation.
The Dalai Lama escaped to India in 1959 and has been
living in exile in Dharamsala ever since.
Dalai Lama (Adult), played by Tenzin Thuthob Tsarong.
Mother, played by Tencho Gyalpo.
Father, played by Tsewang Migyur Khangsar.
Dalai Lama (Age 12), played by Gyurme Tethong.
Chairman Mao, played by Robert Lin.
Dalai Lama (Age 5), played by Tulku Jamyang Kunga Tenzin.
Kundun is a 1997 American epic biographical film written by
Melissa Mathison and directed by Martin Scorsese.
It is based on the life and writings of the 14th Dalai Lama Tenzin Gyatso (known
also as Kundun), the exiled political and spiritual leader of Tibet.
A grandnephew of the Dalai Lama, Tenzin Thuthob Tsarong, stars as the adult Dalai
Lama, while the Dalai Lama's niece Tencho Gyalpo appears as his mother.
The film's release greatly angered the Chinese government, which objected to its content and
threatened to block distributor Disney from accessing the Chinese market as a result.
Disney consequently apologized and limited distribution of the film.
The film explores themes of china, buddhism, buddhist monk, mountain, tibet.
The tone is emotional.